Guide to the James Jesse Strang Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Mormons -- Michigan; Mormons -- Wisconsin; St. James (Mich.); Voree (Wis.); Adams, G. J. (George Jones), 1813-1880; Bennett, John Cook, 1804-1867; Braidwood, Thomas W., 1818-1906; Brownson, George; Chidester, Dennis; Graham, Samuel, fl. 1848-1851; Greig, James M.; Hess, Peter, fl. 1846-1850; Hickey, Lorenzo Dow, 1817-1897; Post, Stephen, fl. 1849-1850; Quaife, Milo Milton, 1880-1959; Smith, William, fl. 1846-1847; Strang, Clement James, 1854-; Strang, James Jesse, 1813-1856; Watson, Gilbert; Watson, Wingfield, 1828-1922; Wright, Benjamin G.; Wright, Zenos H., Mrs.; Associated Order of Enoch; Church of Jesus Christ (Strangites); Order of the Illuminati
- Section A: The Basic Early Documents
  - 1. JAMES J. STRANG. MS Autobiography, 1813-25, written in 1855. 7 p. foolscap. Attached note, unsigned, by his son Charles. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 2. JAMES J. STRANG. Manuscript Diary. Nov 11, 1832- Jun 24, 1835. A fragment of the whole diary. 30 p. 8vo. Now stored with WA MSS S-188 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 3. JAMES J. STRANG. Handmade notebook 12 p. and handmade wrapper, 12mo. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 4. JAMES J. STRANG'S "LETTER OF APPOINTMENT" The account of this famous letter supposedly written by Joseph Smith to James J. Strang from Nauvoo under date of Jun 18, 1844, which Strang first published in the Voree Herald, Jan, 1846, and subsequently in The Diamond (1848), the Prophetic Controversy (1855?), and elsewhere. (Photostat copy stored with collection. Original document is now stored in the Withington File Drawers in the Western Americana stacks, and may be examined upon request). (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted material. A reference surrogate has been substituted in folder 4. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - 5. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. "Memoranda, probably written in late Jul or early Aug, 1844. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 6. JOHN E. PAGE, CHARLES B. THOMPSON, JEHIEL SAVAGE, INCREASE VAN DEUSEN, MOSES SMITH, et al. Manuscript testimony before the High Council at Voree [Apr 6, 1846], 10 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 7. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. fragment written probably in the summer of 1846 for the Herald. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 8. JEHIEL SAVAGE. Manuscript "charges Prefered against Brigham youg Heber Cimble Parley P Pratt" printed in the Voree Herald, Apr, 1846. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 8a. JAMES J. STRANG. Manuscript "Charges," setting forth seven counts against the Twelve Apostles [for trial before the High Council at Voree, Apr 6, 1846]. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 9. JAMES J. STRANG. ALS, dated Ottawa, Ill., Jan 13, 1846. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 10. JOHN E. PAGE. ALS, dated Nauvoo, Feb 1, 1846, to James J. Strang. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 11. BRIGHAM YOUNG. LS, dated Nauvoo, Jan 24, 1846 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - lla. ORSON HYDE [?] MS argument against Strang's claims. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 12. CHARLES GREENWOOD. ALS, dated Boston, Sep 5, 1850, to James J. Strang. 5 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 13. WILLIAM SMITH. ALS, dated Nauvoo, Mar 17, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 14. REUBEN MILLER. ALS, dated Nauvoo, Feb 15, 1845 [i.e., 1846], to James J. Strang at Burlington. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 15. JAMES C. BREWSTER. ALS, dated Springfield, Ill., Mar 15, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 16. BENJAMIN CHAPMAN. ALS, dated Pittsburgh, Mar 24, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 17. P. MATTESON. ALS, dated Elizabeth, Ill., Apr 2, 1846, to James J. Strang at Ottawa, Ill. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 18. JOHN GREENHOW. MS. Statement written for and printed in the Voree Herald, Oct, 1846. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 19. DENNIS CHIDESTER. ALS, dated Milford Centre, [N.Y.], Mar 13, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 20. JAMES W. PUGH. ALS, dated Cincinnati, Mar 23, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 21. JAMES J. STRANG. Manuscripts of 2 items prepared by Strang for publication in the Herald. Apr and May, 1846. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 22. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to James Smith at Pittsburgh, dated Ottaway, Apr 22, 1846. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 22a. JAMES SMITH. ALS, dated Pittsburgh, May 16, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 23. CALVIN B. CHILDS. ALS, dated Black River, Jefferson Co., N.Y., Apr 26, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 24. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Cincinnati, Apr 2, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 25. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. articles prepared for publication in the Voree Herald, 1846 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 26. LUCY SMITH. Contemporary copy of her letter of Mar 22, 1846 3 p., 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 27. WILLIAM SMITH. ALS, dated Knoxville, (Ill.,) Dec 7, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 27a. WILLIAM SMITH. ALS, dated Knoxville, (Ill.), Dec 14, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 2 p. foolscap and attached slip. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 27b. WILLIAM SMITH. ALS, dated Knoxville, (Ill). Dec 25 1846, to James J. Strang. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 28. JAMES J. STRANG, MS. Memorandum, 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 29. ESTHER ORMSBY. ALS, dated Manachuashaw or Waterloo, Wis., May 17, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 30. ISAAC PADEN. ALS, dated Knoxville, May 17, 1846 to James J. Strang. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 31. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to unknown feminine correspondent, Voree, May 23, 1846. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 32. REUBEN MILLER. ALS, dated No(r)way, (Ill.) May 24, 1846, to James J. Strang at Ottawa, Ill. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 33. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Plymouth, Mass., Jun 2 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 33a. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated (ca. Mar 1846), to James J. Strang at Voree. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 33b. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Cincinnati, Mar (23?), 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 33c. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Cincinnati, Mar 27, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 34. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS, dated Cincinnati, Mar 27, 1845, to James J. Strang at Voree. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 34a. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS, dated Lewisburg, Ohio, Jun 3, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 6 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 34b. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS, dated Lewisburgh, Ohio, Jun 20, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 35. JOHN E. PAGE. ALS, dated Elgin, Ill., Jul 6, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 36. SAMUEL MOORE REEVE. ALS, dated Philadelphia, Jul 12, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 37. LOUISA S (LOUISA SANGER?) ALS, dated Ottawa, (Ill.) Jul 15, (1846), to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 37a. LOUISA S (LOUISA SANGER?) ALS, n.p., (ca. Nov 1846), to James J. Strang at Burlington. 2 p. 8vo. in pencil. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 38. (JOHN C. BENNETT.) MS. Minutes of the High Council at Voree, Oct 4, 1846. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 38a. JOHN C. BENNETT. MS. in his hand extracting from the Times and Seasons, Jun 15, 1842, p. 830, the notice of his withdrawal from the Church on May 11, 1842. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 39. WILLARD GRIFFITH. MS. Statement dated Voree, Oct 23, 1846. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 40. JAMES J. STRANG, et al. MS. statement by the presiding officers of the Church (ca. Oct 1846). 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 41. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of revelation, Oct 18, 1846. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 42. EBENEZER PAGE. ALS, dated Antwerp, N.Y., Nov 3, 1846, to James J. Strang. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 43. JAMES BLANCHARD. ALS, dated Oquawka, Ill., Nov 6, 1846, to William Smith at Knoxville, Ill. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 43a. With this: Note by William Smith, (n.d.). 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 44. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 45. PETER HESS. ALS, dated Philadelphia, Dec 14, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 46. REUBEN MILLER. ALS, dated Burlington, Wis., Dec 23, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p., 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 47. REUBEN MILLER. MS. Notes in an unknown hand. 2 p. foolscap (In pencil.) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 48. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. Refutatlon of Reuben Miller's discourse against him of Jul 25, 1846. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 49. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. article entitled "Reubenism." 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 50. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. plan for arcees of Voree Temple, with diagrams. (ca. 1847?). 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 51. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. plan for Voree Temple or Tabernacle? (ca. 1847?). 1 p. foolscap? in pencil. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 52. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. article (prepared for and printed in the Voree Herald, Oct, 1846). 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 53. JOHN E. PAGE. ALS, dated Kings Mills (Ill.), Jan 23, 1847, to John Greenhow. at Voree. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 54. LESTER BROOKS. ALS, dated Laporte, Lorain Co., Ohio, Jan 12, 1847, to James M. Adams at Voree. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 55. LOUISA S (LOUISA SANGER?) ALS, dated Ottawa, (Ill.,) Aug 19, (1849), to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 56. CHARLES DURKEE. ALS, dated Washington, Jan 13, 1850, to James J. Strang. Encloses him a reply from the Swedish consul to Strang's inquiry. 1 p. 8vo. with this: Durkee to Strang, Jan 4, 1850, transmitting a 3 p. ALS by H. (?) Habicht of the Swedish consulate in New York. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 57. WILFORD WOODRUFF. ALS, dated Cambridgeport, Mass. Jan 11, 1850, to J. W. Grierson (at Washington). 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 58. JOHN W. GRIERSON. ALS, dated Washington, Jan 22, 1850, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. Encloses to Strang Woodruff's letter of Jan 11, 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 59. ENOS GOODRICH. ALS, dated Goodrich, (Mich.?) Mar 7, 1853, to Chas. E. Stuart. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Section B: Personal Papers
  Scope and Contents
  Strang's original draft letters, writings, and family correspondence
  - 60. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to John C. Bennett, dated Voree, May 5, 1846. Draft of letter to George J. Adams, Voree, May 5, 1846. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 61. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to (I. A. Hopkins), dated Burlington, Wis., Dec 21, 1846. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 62. JAMES J. STRANG. ALS, dated Racine, (Wis.), Jun 13, 1849, to Benjamin G. Wright at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (On same sheet) Wright's reply dated Voree, Jun 15, 1850. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 63. E. B. FAIRFIELD. ALS, dated Spring Arbre, (Mich.,) Jul 30, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 63a. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of reply to above, dated Voree, Aug 11, 1849. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 64. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter dated Racine, (Wis.,) Sep 1, 1849. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 65. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to M. Lindley, dated Baltimore, Md., Nov 13, 1849. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 66. JOHN URSBRUCK. ALS, dated Philadelphia, Nov 17, 1849 to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 66a. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of reply to above, dated Baltimore, Nov 20, 1849. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 67. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to Andrew Graham, dated Baltimore, Md., Nov 19, 1843. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 68. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to Peter Hess, dated Baltimore, Md., Nov 20, 1849. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 69. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to (Amos Lowen), dated Baltimore, Nov 21, 1849. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 70. PETER HESS. ALS, dated Philadelphia, Nov 22, 1849, James J. Strang at Baltimore. 10 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 70a. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to Peter Hess, dated Baltimore, Md., Nov 23, 1849. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 71. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to L. D. Hickey, Baltimore, Md., Dec 10, 1849. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 72. JAMES J. STRANG. Dranft of letter to Rev. Mr. Cook, dated Baltimore, Md., Jan 16, 1850. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 73. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to wife, Mary Perce Strang, dated Baltimore, Md., Jan 25, 1850. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 74. JAMES J. STRANG. ALS, dated Saint James, May 19, 1851 to Deawn (?) Clement Strang, Cherry Creek, N.Y. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 74a. Note to wife Mary. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 75. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to unidentified woman, (n.p., n.d.). 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 76. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of opinion on the validity of the marriage of Br. & Sr. Andrews. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 77. JAMES J. STRANG. Drafts of patriarchal blessings upon the heads of Zimri and Philetta Butterfield, Voree, Aug 23, 1849. 2 pieces. each 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 78. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of patriarchal blessing on A. L. Hosmer, Nov 27, 1849. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 79. JAMES J. STRANG. MS Memorandum: (1846?) 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 80. JAMES J. STRANG. MS Commandment. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 81. JAMES J. STRANG. MS Commandment. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 82. JAMES J. STRANG. MS draft of the opening para- graphs of what was intended as the first of a series of brief articles on the State of Deseret. Baltimore, Jan 1850?). 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 83. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. minutes of a sermon (n.p., n.d.) Also includes 7 lines of minutes from a meeting "Monday as per adj., with Br. Graham pleading the cause of the poor." (ca. Jul, 1850?). 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 84. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. of his sixth argument in his debate in the Herald with Mr. Briggs on the topic, "Existence of God." Dated Voree, Jan 16, 1849. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 85. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. of his contemplated article for the Plymouth, Mass., Old Colony Memorial. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 86. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. notes on Biblical kings. (ca. Dec 1849?) 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 87. (JAMES J. STRANG) MS. Constitution of Reformed Temperance Society. (Baltimore, Md.? ca. Dec, 1849?) 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 88. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. notes on debate with (___) McCabe on Mormonism. (n.d.). 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 89. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. notes on the Deluge, Baltimore, Md., Dec 9, 1849. 6 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 90. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. lecture notes on Mormonism. ALSO: penciled notes hostile to both Strang and Joseph Smith. (n.d. ca. 1849?). 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 91. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. note on "Compromises," 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 92. JAMES J. STRANG (?) Notes evidently made in the Michigan legislature during the progress of a debate. (185?). 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 93. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. license to preach. Elkhorn Jun 13, 1846. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 94. JAMES W. BARTHOLF. ALS, dated Voree, Jul 27, 1846, to George Thompson & the Brethren in the Branch at Batavia, Geneva Co., N.Y. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 95. JAMES J. STRANG. Hair locks in ornamental designs, presented to Strang (?) at Rutland Hollow, N.Y., Jun 23, 1847, by Lucy Waldo, Olive Scott, Lucretia Wait, Mary Ann Barker, and Jane Brown. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 96. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. license to preach. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 97. (C. P. BARNES.) Facetious note to James J. Strang signed "I Snort Atty for Plff." 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 98. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. poem in three stanzas, from a note by Strang in later years. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 99. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. Assignment to Strang dated Ellington (N.Y.,) Jun 2, 1841, and discharge by him dated Sep 20, 1845. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 100. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. notes on debate Seth W. Chandler, Oct 2, 1841. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 101. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. decision by Henry D. Grant, Ellington, (N.Y.), Nov 6, 1841. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 102. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. notes (incomplete) on debate before the Ellington Lyceum, Nov 20, 1841. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 103. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. scientific notes as to evolution, geology, astronomy, etc. Endorsed: "Lecture, June 30, 1842." 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 104. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. contract between Strang and James Beardsley, Jan 13, 1842, at Ellington. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 105. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. accounts, Feb 16-Jun 31 1843. 9 p. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 106. JAMES J. STRANG. Bill submitted to Strang May 20, 1853, by R. B. Clark. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 107. D. BENEDICT. ALS, dated Pawtucket, [ [, Mar 10, 1843, to B. Pearce, Burlington, Wis. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 108. JAMES J. STRANG. Draft of letter to M. Stroper at Hanover, dated Randolph, Jun 27, 1843. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 109. SAMUEL A. BROWN. ALS, dated Westfield, [N.Y.,] Aug 16, 1843, to Henry Brown at Chicago. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 110. JAMES J. STRANG. MS. arbitration of suit against Horatio and Ebben Hill. [n.d.]. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 111. MANNING J. HANNAMAN. ALS, dated Knoxville, [Ill.,] Feb 25, 1847, to James J. Strang at Burlington. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 112. ANDREW CALHOUN. Power of attorney authorizing James J. Strang to act for him with respect to a certain demand against Joseph Peirse [?], dated Feb 16, 1849. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 113. MARY PERCE STRANG. ALS, dated [n.p.] Nov 4, 1849, to James J. Strang at New York City. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 114. MARY PERCE STRANG. ALS, dated [n.p., ca. Dec 1849] to James J. Strang. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 115. MARY PERCE STRANG. ALS, dated Cherry Creek, [N.Y.,] Jan 9, 1850, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 116. MARY PERCE STRANG. ALS, dated [Cherry Creek, N.Y., ca. Nov 10, 1849, to James J. Strang. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 117. [MOTHER] ABIGAIL STRANG. ALS, dated [n.p., ca. May? 1850], to James J. Strang. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 118. [MOTHER] ABIGAIL STRANG. ALS, dated Cherry Creek, [N.Y.,] Nov 1, 1850, to James J. Strang. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 119. [MOTHER] ABIGAIL STRANG. ALS, dated Cherry Creek, N.Y., ca. Jun 23, 1851(?), to James J. Strang. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 120. [SISTER] MYRAETTE A. LOSEE. ALS, dated Cherry Creek, [N.Y.,] May 5, 1846, to James J. Strang. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 121. [SISTER] MYRAETTE A. LOSEE. ALS, dated Cherry Creek, [N.Y.,] Aug 20, 1846, to James J. Strang at New York. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 122. [SISTER] MYRAETTE A. LOSEE. ALS, dated Cherry Creek, [N.Y.,] Dec 8, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 123. [SISTER] MYRAETTE A. LOSEE. ALS, dated Cherry Creek [N.Y.,] May 13, 1847, to James J. Strang at Burlington. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 124. [SISTER] MYRAETTE A. LOSEE. ALS, dated Cherry Creek, [N.Y.,] Nov 20, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 125. [SISTER] MARY A. LOSEE. ALS, dated Cherry Creek, [N.Y.,] Jul 23, 1845, to James J. Strang, Burlington, Wis. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 126. [BROTHER] DAVID STRANG. ALS, dated [Randolph, N.Y.,] Aug 11, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 127. [BROTHER] DAVID STRANG. ALS, dated Kenqua [Kenzua?] N.Y., May 28, 1848 [?], to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 128. [BROTHER] DAVID STRANG. ALS, dated Kenqua [?] N.Y., Jun 24, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 129. J. N. JAMES. ALS, dated Jamesville, [N.Y.], Jan 8, 1851, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 130. POLLY JAMES. ALS, dated Jamesville, [N.Y.,] Aug 26, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree, with draft of reply to JAMES J. STRANG, dated Baltimore, Dec 24, 1849. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 131. JOHN DENNISON. ALS, dated Hagerstown, Md., Mar 13, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 132. JOHN DENNISON. ALS, dated Alden, N.Y., Jul 11, 1849, to James J. Strang. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 133. Letter addressed "Dear Sister" dated Ligoneer [?] Noble Co. Ind. Jan 1, 1864, followed on the verso by a message headed "from Mary Jane to Elizabeth Strang" 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 134. Apparently this is the commencement of a letter written at some time after Strang's death, perhaps in the sixties, by one of his widows. The later date of the fragment is indicated by the reference to Samuel Seaman, who was a son of Murry Seeman, a firm Strangite. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 135. [MOTHER] L. PERCE. ALS, dated Morris, [I11.,] Sep 20, 1846, to Mary A. P. Strang. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 136. EDWARD LEARNED. ALS, dated West Troy, N.Y., Apr 9, 1849, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 137. J. N. BACON. ALS, dated Newton, [N.Y.?], Apr 13, 1848, to James J. Strang. 2 pieces, each 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 138. SAMUEL G. PERCE. ALS, dated Dundee, May 5, 1850, to James J. Strang. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 139. SAMUEL G[?]. PERCE. ALS, dated Chicago, Feb 10, 1850, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. [Note: Samuel Perce was Strang's brother-in-law.] (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 140. SAMUEL PERCE. ALS, dated Belvidere, [Ill.,] Jun 5, 1850. to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 141. W. E. PERCE. ALS, dated Voree, Sep 18, 1849, to James J. Strang at Buffalo. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 142. W. L. PERCE. ALS, dated Elgin, [Ill.,] Jan 7, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 143. W. L. PERCE, JR. ALS, dated Green River, [Wis.,] Jun 3, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 144. W. L. PERCE, ALS, dated Green River, [Wis.,] Jun 3, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 145. W. L. PERCE, JR. ALS, dated Elgin, [Ill.,] Nov 10, 1850, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 146. CHARLES J. DOUGLASS [pseudonym for ELVIRA FIELD, first plural wife of James J. Strang]. ALS, dated Baltimore, Feb 4, 1850, to James J. Strang. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 147. CHARLES J. DOUGLASS [pseudonym ELVIRA FIELD]. ALS, dated Baltimore, Feb 7, 1850, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 148. F. MERRYWEATHER. ALS, dated Nashville, [Tenn.,] Nov 29, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 149. JOHN E. PAGE. ALS, dated St. Charles, Ill., Jan 1, 1847, to James J. Strang. 4 p. 4to. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 150. INCREASE VAN DEUSEN. ALS, dated Syracuse, N.Y., Jan 3, 1847, to J. B. Wheeland at Voree. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 151. JOHN W. CRANE. ALS, dated Knoxville, I11., Jan 9, 1847, to James J. Strang at Burlington. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 152. [UNSIGNED.] AL, dated Lockport, [N.Y.,] Mar 26, 1847 to James J. Strang at Burlington. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 153. INCREASE VAN DEUSEN. ALS, dated New York, Jun 18, 1849, to [James J. Strang.] 4 p. foolscap (Box 1, Folder 30)